Dillon Streator

Developer

SKILLS

Schaumburg, Illinois US

☑ dillonstreator@gmail.com











I am highly passionate about web development and security. I like to think I am a connoisseur of clean and concise code; a way of being which has been developed over the years working with some of the most pervasive frameworks to the more obscure, giving me a breadth of reference. I truly enjoy transforming dreams into system requirements and ultimately into concrete products.

Frontend	Frontend Frameworks	Backend
HTML CSS SCSS Javascript Typescript	React Vue Angular	Node Typescript Golang Ruby Java Python PHP
Backend Frameworks	Database	APIs
Expresjs Gatsbyjs Nextjs Strapijs Spring Boot Ruby on Rails	MSSQL Postgresql Mysql MongoDB	Graphql RESTful RPC
CMS	etc.	
Contentful Strapijs WordPress Shopify	git TDD Extreme Programming NPM bundler gradle Pivotal Cloud Foundry AWS Netlify Vercel Jenkins TravisCI Codecov Kibana Datadog Sentry Grafana Docker docker-compose Kubernetes Whitesource Veracode Contrast Twistlock Nexpose 12 Factor Applications	

WORK EXPERIENCE (4)

Full Stack Developer at Enova

Mar 2020 - Current

Chicago, IL https://www.enova.com

- Tech Stack: Golang, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Vue, React, Enzyme, Codecov, SQS, Docker, Kubernetes
- Built an internal SCA scanner service with an HTTP API that supports golang, ruby, and javascript projects and supports monolithic applications. This was done in the mindset of the Enova value of 'Operating as an Owner'. I saw a need for a service and implemented it.
- Working to extract financial accounting from a legacy monolith system to a new micro-service based system.
- Working to drive the initiative of enterprise containerization.
- Implementing neglected frontend test coverage on React and Vue applications using Enzyme.

- Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot, JPA, JUnit, Mockito, PowerMockito, React, Redux, react-router, Normalizer, Jest, Enzyme, fetch-mock, Node, Express, super-test, Docker, Jenkins, Cloud Foundry, Kibana, Graphana, MS Suite
- Developing internal systems to provide secure application deployment across the enterprise utilizing modern webframeworks, standards and security practices.
- Actively engaged in TDD and XP practices.
- Wrote both Unit and Integration/End to End testing.
- Followed best practices with regards to CI/CD deployments.
- Wrote scalable and maintainable code following 12 factor and SOLID principles.
- Worked with/on Monolith and Microservice based applications/systems.
- Integrated with a variety of 3rd party APIs including: Veracode, Whitesource, Contrast, Twistlock, Nexpose/Rapid7, VersionOne, MS Teams, etc.

Director of Development at Youtech

Jun 2018 - Jan 2019

Naperville, IL https://www.youtechagency.com

- Maintained and grew new and existing client relationships.
- Managed a team of 7 developers both local and remote.
- Implemented workflow standardizations; including git, code reviews, and testing.
- Conducted meetings on both a team and personal level.
- Personal & professional development of team through promoting sponsored events and lightning talks/lunch and learns.

Full Stack Developer at Youtech

Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

Naperville, IL https://www.youtechagency.com

- Tech Stack: Node, Express, EJS, Angular 2+, RxJS, NativeScript, MongoDB, Mongoose, MYSQL, MSSQL, Magento, WordPress, Shopify
- Independently planned, prioritized, and executed development of complex custom web and mobile applications.
- Interfaced with external and internal clients from design to marketing to C-suite executives and stakeholders on project needs and status.
- Troubleshot abd resolve WordPress and Magento third party plugin/extension installation conflicts/incompatibilities.
- Created custom WordPress and Magento plugin/extensions.

PROJECTS (1) -

Slixites Aug 2020 - Current

https://www.slixites.com

Gatsbyjs Web development consulting

VOLUNTEER

Full Stack Developer at The Difference Engine

May 2017 - Sep 2017

Web development services provided for non-profit organizations in the Chicago-land area

- Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, React, rspec, Stripe, Devise, SendGrid Developed admin workspace, and database architecture.
- Provided a full stack e-commerce solution for a non-profit coffee subscription startup.

Bootcamp Software Development at Actualize				
AAS Electronics Engineering at Harper College			2017 - 2017 2014 - 2016	
PUBLICATIONS —				
Slixites Blog in Dillon Streator				
LANGUAGES				
English Native speaker				
Sport	Music	etc.		
Boxing/Thai Boxing Ping Pong	House The Rat Pack India	e Travel Pizza		
Pool Bowling Kayaking	Alternative 90s			

EDUCATION (2)